{"tossups": [{"question": "This man was described as \u201cproudly standing in his tiny swimsuit among the bikini-clad starlets despite a new pacemaker visible under his chest\u201d in a eulogy written for him by James Rosenquist. An untitled Donald Judd sculpture subtitled \u201cfor [this man]\u201d consists of five concrete cubes with two missing sides each. This man\u2019s (+) clients the Sculls and the Tremaines feuded over ownership of a 1961 painting, the largest its artist had ever made, before it was ultimately donated to MoMA. Jackson Pollock\u2019s Number 1 was featured at this man\u2019s Ninth Street Show, which featured a then-unknown (*) Robert Rauschenberg. This man paid artists regardless of their work selling as part of his stipend system and could sell \u201ctwo beer cans\u201d according to Willem de Kooning. This man often worked with Sidney Janis prior to opening his own gallery and gave Jasper Johns and Roy Lichtenstein their first solo shows. For 10 points, identify this late 20th century Italian-American art dealer.", "answer": "Leo Castelli (accept Leo Krausz) [The painting in line five is Map by Jasper Johns.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Leo Castelli</u></b> [The painting in line five is Map by Jasper Johns.]", "acceptable": ["Leo Castelli", "Leo Castelli"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Leo Krausz"}, {"question": "This is the most famous painting in a series described by Georgia O\u2019Keeffe as \u201ca brass band in a closet.\u201d This painting \u201cstood as a symbol for all that is inspiring in young life\u201d according to its artist. A central object in this painting is placed inside of a green circle, a red circle, a blue triangle, and a yellow triangle. A white line connecting to a star representing a (+) boot spur appears to the left of two white tassels in this painting. Two curvilinear letter \u201cE\u201ds in this painting potentially refer to the artist\u2019s birth name, Edmund. A yellow number \u201c24\u201d appears to the right of St. (*) George\u2019s Cross in this painting, above which is a yellow-trimmed epaulette. Several checkerboard patterns appear above a red, white, and black tricolor in this painting. The flag of Bavaria appears below an iron cross in this painting, which was created as a tribute to the artist\u2019s potential lover, Karl von Freyburg, who died in battle in 1914. For 10 points, identify this painting by Marsden Hartley.", "answer": "Portrait of a German Officer", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Portrait of a German Officer</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Portrait of a German Officer", "Portrait of a German Officer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A performance titled for this substance required deep-sea divers to place a glass vitrine filled with several drawings and a bronze book underwater three months prior to its enactment. A sculpture made of this substance is housed in a Perspex box filled with silicone oil and is replaced every five years by its creator in an homage to Rembrandt. An artwork titled for this substance was (+) photographed against a spray-painted background in Leon Golub\u2019s studio in 1985. The carcass of a dogfish shark was carried in a wooden cart and later fed to visitors as part of a performance piece by Elizabeth Peyton and Matthew Barney titled [this substance] of (*) Two. Ten pints of this substance were used by Marc Quinn in a sculpture of his own head titled Self. It\u2019s not urine, but a plexiglass cross filled with this substance was photographed by Andres Serrano. For 10 points, identify this biological substance that exited Christ\u2019s hands after nails were run through them.", "answer": "blood (accept Blood of Two; accept Blood Cross)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>blood</u></b>", "acceptable": ["blood", "blood"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Blood of Two; accept Blood Cross"}, {"question": "A sculpture by an artist with this surname allows viewers to spin a multicolored wheel that opens compartments containing objects from various cities around the world. An artist with this surname was buried in a Packard car with a bottle of Chianti and the ashes of his pet dog. One work by an artist with this last name was described as a place where people \u201cwaste time, kill time, forget time, and ignore time\u201d and features several (+) clocks set to 10:10. An artist with this surname showed a giraffe with crutches in a sculpture of a dilapidated carousel titled The Merry-Go-World. A sculpture by an artist with this surname includes a pink neon outline of a text box and live black fish inside of bowls in place of the (*) heads of two figures. An artist with this surname used a bunk-bed in his work The State Hospital and created a walk-in installation titled The Beanery. For 10 points, identify this surname of American artists Nancy and Edward.", "answer": "Kienholz (accept Edward Ralph Kienholz or Nancy Reddin Kienholz; prompt on \u201cReddin\u201d with \u201cWhat was her married name?\u201d)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Kienholz</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Kienholz", "Kienholz"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Edward Ralph Kienholz or Nancy Reddin Kienholz; prompt on \u201cReddin\u201d with \u201cWhat was her married name?\u201d"}, {"question": "Two answers required. One of these artists gave a nickname to the other referring to Wilbur Wright due to his many innovations. One of these artists once described their work with the other as \u201cbeing roped together on a mountain.\u201d One of these artist\u2019s paintings of an olive tree and the other\u2019s painting titled for a (+) Pigeon with Peas were among several stolen from the MAM Paris in 2010. One of these artists described feeling a \u201cgreat shock\u201d upon creating one piece, with the other feeling an \u201ceven greater shock\u201d upon it being shown to him; that piece includes the word \u201cBAR\u201d in the top right. One of these artist\u2019s paintings, The Portuguese, and the other\u2019s painting (*) Ma Jolie are often difficult to differentiate from each other due to their extreme stylistic similarity. Fruit Dish and Glass utilizes the papier coll\u00e9 technique pioneered by these two artists who also began the analytic and synthetic phases of a certain movement. For 10 points, identify these two co-founders of Cubism.", "answer": "Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque (accept Pablo Diego Jos\u00e9 Francisco de Paula Juan Nepomuceno Mar\u00eda de los Remedios Cipriano de la Sant\u00edsima Trinidad Ruiz y Picasso and Georges Braque)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque", "Pablo Picasso and Georges Braque"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Pablo Diego Jos\u00e9 Francisco de Paula Juan Nepomuceno Mar\u00eda de los Remedios Cipriano de la Sant\u00edsima Trinidad Ruiz y Picasso and Georges Braque"}, {"question": "In one poem, this author described being unable to open a red door and being uninterested by a gray door, and subsequently looking out of a window instead. This author never published their partial autobiography titled China Eggs. An egg appears next to a wall with a rounded opening in a painting by this artist associated with their poem of the same name, My Room Has Two Doors. Gray humanoid forms appear within several (+) towers of scaffolding above a sea of gray fog in this artist\u2019s painting Tomorrow is Never. Stairsteps appear below a cloth wrapped through a head in a work by this artist potentially depicting themselves, titled Small Portrait. Many canvases and stretchers sit on an endless gray plane in this artist\u2019s painting The Answer is No, which may call back to the large mass of misshapen gray objects in her (*) husband\u2019s painting Multiplication of the Arcs. For 10 points, identify this woman, a Surrealist artist and poet who married Yves Tanguy.", "answer": "Kay Sage (accept Katherine Linn Sage)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Kay <b><u>Sage</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Kay Sage", "Sage"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Katherine Linn Sage"}, {"question": "A follow-up to a work titled for this person alluded to the quote \u201c...and never shall the twain meet\u201d with its title, \u201cBye Bye Kipling.\u201d This man titles a work that featured a performance of a man stroking dried cactus needles with a feather. A work titled for this man opens with a pair of lips repeating its title phrase in English and French as (+) pixelated lightning bolts strike around it. In one work, text about this man plays as Merce Cunningham dances with bandone\u00f3n music in the background. A work titled for this man featured a failed attempt at a \u201cspace yodel\u201d and a performance of \u201cExcellent Birds\u201d by Laurie Anderson and Peter Gabriel. George Plimpton hosted that work titled for this man that was (*) watched live by 25 million people and connected Paris\u2019s Pompidou Centre and WNET TV in New York via satellite. Nam June Paik coordinated a New Year\u2019s Day television broadcast titled Good Morning, [this man]. For 10 points, identify this author of 1984.", "answer": "George Orwell (accept Eric Arthur Blair; accept Good Morning, Mr. Orwell)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "George <b><u>Orwell</u></b>", "acceptable": ["George Orwell", "Orwell"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Eric Arthur Blair; accept Good Morning, Mr. Orwell"}, {"question": "ANSWER: George Orwell (accept Eric Arthur Blair; accept Good Morning, Mr. Orwell) <Visual Fine Arts> 8. This painting was given to the museum where it is currently housed by Sigfried Sassoon in honor of its artist\u2019s grandnephew Julian. A figure in this painting has a triple crown in a likely reference to the Pope, whom the artist was overwhelmed by an urge to attack after seeing him during a visit to Rome. The line \u201cAnd nothing from nothing nothing gains\u201d ends a poem by this painting\u2019s artist meant to expand on its (+) characters and titled for an \u201cElimination of a Picture & its Subject.\u201d This painting, which titles a song involving a \u201cquaere fellow\u201d on the album Queen II, was considered to be unfinished by its artist due to its bottom left corner only being sketched in. The title figure of this painting raises an axe over a (*) chestnut that will be used to construct a carriage. This painting was created for G. H. Haydon following its artist\u2019s incarceration at Bethlem Hospital for murdering his father in 1843. For 10 points, identify this painting by Richard Dadd.", "answer": "The Fairy-Feller\u2019s Master Stroke", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Fairy-Feller\u2019s Master Stroke</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Fairy-Feller\u2019s Master Stroke", "Fairy-Feller\u2019s Master Stroke"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one essay, this type of pattern \u201cextends, in all directions, to infinity\u201d and is described as \u201cthe symbol of the symbolist work of art\u201d during a section about windows. A large amount of stuffed animals appear above one of these patterns made with wood in Leonardo Drew\u2019s Number 74. This type of pattern is overlaid onto scribbles of orange, white, and blue in the first entry of Cy Twombly\u2019s Nine Discourses on Commodus series. One of these patterns \u201cfunctions to declare the modernity of modern art\u201d in an essay titled for them by (+) Rosalind Krauss. Steel Zinc Plain is one of the many sculptures in this type of pattern created by Carl Andre. Squiggly lines and orange circles appear on one of these patterns with Symbols in a work by (*) Alexander Calder. Chuck Close often divided his paintings into this sort of pattern to maintain proportional scale. For 10 points, identify this sort of pattern, a network of lines that cross to make a series of squares or rectangles.", "answer": "grids (accept anything implying squares or rectangles in a pattern before stated; accept checkerboard; prompt on \u2018lines\u2019 or anything not necessarily implying a grid; do not accept answers involving other shapes)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>grids</u></b>", "acceptable": ["grids", "grids"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept anything implying squares or rectangles in a pattern before stated; accept checkerboard; prompt on \u2018lines\u2019 or anything not necessarily implying a grid; do not accept answers involving other shapes"}, {"question": "Following his most famous work, this artist fleshed out his ideas in works like \u201cThe Realm of the Senses\u201d and \u201cThe Formation of the Individual.\u201d This artist splashed red and brown oil paint onto a boar\u2019s hide mounted on a canvas in multiple works subtitled for Wild Boar Hunting. This artist wrote that he had \u201clong been obsessed with how art as the expression of the spirit is contingent on the body\u201d in his essay \u201cOn (+) Shishitsu.\u201d In one work, an eight-meter-long white wooden plank was sawed in half by this artist\u2019s wife Fujiko. Characters from Water Margin title several works by this artist that he created by tying a rope to the ceiling of his studio and swinging on it to paint with his feet. In his most well known work, this artist (*) stripped down to a loincloth in the courtyard of the Ohara Kaikan and struggled in a mix of cement, sand, gravel, and kabetsuchi. For 10 points, identify this member of the Gutai Art Association known for his performance Challenging Mud.", "answer": "Kazuo Shiraga", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Kazuo <b><u>Shiraga</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Kazuo Shiraga", "Shiraga"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Coins spill out of a lopsided crown that represents greed in a series of seven deadly sins themed pi\u00f1atas housed at this location. The face of Willie Nelson is superimposed over the faces of people at this location at the end of a video centering on it. This location is home to a \u201cBirth of Venus (+) Party Platter\u201d and multiple raw chickens covered in tattoos. In this location, a river of \u201cSource\u201d splits a place known as \u201cthe forked earth\u201d that can be accessed through a curvy tunnel inside of a soda freezer. Along with Santa Fe\u2019s House of Eternal Return and Denver\u2019s Convergence Station, this (*) installation was created by the arts company Meow Wolf. A fake PSA for this location advises its customers to return one of its products that resembles a lemon with an eyeball and ends with its tagline, \u201cyou have no idea what\u2019s in-store for you!\u201d For 10 points, identify this interactive Las Vegas art installation that depicts a supermarket named for the last letter of the Greek alphabet.", "answer": "Omega Mart [The pi\u00f1atas in the first line were designed by Justin Favela.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Omega Mart</u></b> [The pi\u00f1atas in the first line were designed by Justin Favela.]", "acceptable": ["Omega Mart", "Omega Mart"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Two answers required. These two artists were the subject of a 2014 exhibition at the Blanton Museum of Art titled Converging Lines. One of these artists told the other to \u201cstop worrying about big, deep things\u201d and to instead \u201cpractice being stupid, dumb, unthinking, [and] empty\u201d in a work that shows the word (+) \u201cDO\u201d surrounded by lines and arrows. One of these artists responded to the other\u2019s frequent use of cubes with a work made of galvanized steel and rubber tubing that was their first attempt at working with outside fabricators. One of these artists advised the other to \u201ctry the most outrageous things you can - shock yourself\u201d in a letter, after which the other created a sculpture of a (*) frame with a cord jutting out from it titled Hang-Up. One of these artists used \u201cnot straight\u201d pencil lines for the first time in his Wall Drawing #46 upon his learning of the other\u2019s death of a brain tumor at age 34. For 10 points, identify these two Post-Minimalist artists.", "answer": "Eva Hesse and Sol Lewitt (accept \u201cSolomon\u201d in place of \u201cSol\u201d) [The work in line five is Accession V.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Eva Hesse and Sol Lewitt</u></b> [The work in line five is Accession V.]", "acceptable": ["Eva Hesse and Sol Lewitt", "Eva Hesse and Sol Lewitt"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept \u201cSolomon\u201d in place of \u201cSol\u201d"}, {"question": "\u201cThe sky shone with red flowers of Christ\u201d and \u201cdeath embraced many beautiful and hopeful people\u201d after this event according to a dramatic retelling of it written by Lajos Kass\u00e1k. Large ovular trees and two poles are visible in the background of a pastel on paper study for a painting of this event, which was likely changed after its artist saw examples of (+) Cubism while in Paris. Alfred H. Barr, Jr described a painting of this event as being \u201cas classically organized as a fifteenth-century battle piece by Paolo Uccello.\u201d During this event, an artist \u201csaw horses go mad, sticks and lances clash\u201d and was concerned that a central object would fall to the ground and be trampled. A painting of this event shows several (*) black flags in the air and an orange coffin being held by a mass of people in the center. For 10 points, name this event depicted in a 1911 Futurist painting by Carlo Carr\u00e1 in which a violent riot occurred following the death of an Italian anarchist.", "answer": "the funeral of Angelo Galli (accept The Funeral of the Anarchist Galli; accept anything involving a riot or police fight so long as it mentions the funeral or death of Angelo Galli; prompt on partial answers)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>funeral of Angelo Galli</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the funeral of Angelo Galli", "funeral of Angelo Galli"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept The Funeral of the Anarchist Galli; accept anything involving a riot or police fight so long as it mentions the funeral or death of Angelo Galli; prompt on partial answers"}, {"question": "Four clothes hangers are attached to a cross in this artist\u2019s sculpture Form Follows Function. This artist installed binoculars to an extension of the Tate Modern in a guerrilla work titled Please Respect Our Neighbors\u2019 Privacy. One work by this artist consists of a several meters long tunnel in the ground whose inside is completely plastered with images of (+) Kim Kardashian. After being asked by Gucci to interpret what beauty means today, this artist hired a caricaturist to depict several of their models. Due to several delayed flights, the singer Sigrid was unable to appear in the music video for her song \u201cMine Right Now,\u201d resulting in this artist having to take her place. Six white blocks surround a central block topped with a solar-powered (*) MP3 player connecting to several speakers in this artist\u2019s most famous work, which is installed at an undisclosed place in the Namib desert and continuously plays the song Africa. For 10 points, identify this artist of Toto Forever.", "answer": "Max Siedentopf (accept Maximilian Siedentopf) [The work in line three is Tribute.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Max <b><u>Siedentopf</u></b> [The work in line three is Tribute.]", "acceptable": ["Max Siedentopf", "Siedentopf"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Maximilian Siedentopf"}, {"question": "A quote about certain \u201cflat-chested\u201d birds \u201cstrutting upon the intellectual wastelands and beaches\u201d was referenced in the title of a Time magazine article about this group titled The Revolt of the Pelicans. A claim that this group had committed a \u201cdistortion of fact\u201d was published in an editorial by Emily Genauer, who first coined the name of this group. Due to previously (+) running for mayor of New York City, one member of this group had a work involving it published on the front page of the New York Times. In one work, this group was arranged \u201clike bankers\u201d and depicted one of its members standing on a table after she arrived late. Francis Taylor\u2019s choice of (*) jurors for the exhibition American Painting Today - 1950 resulted in this group signing an open letter to the Met and boycotting the exhibition, shortly before appearing in a photograph for Life magazine. For 10 points, identify this group of American abstract artists who appear in an iconic photograph by Nina Leen.", "answer": "The Irascibles (accept The Irascible 18; prompt on answers involving \u201cabstract expressionism\u201d)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Irascibles</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Irascibles", "Irascibles"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept The Irascible 18; prompt on answers involving \u201cabstract expressionism\u201d"}, {"question": "Four felt triangles, mirrors, and an angled shelf appear in a Saint George and the Dragon-inspired entry in this artist\u2019s Partitions series. This artist described their work as \u201cnot only looked at, but lived\u201d in their statement \u201cBefore May 1968.\u201d Two voices read letters aloud as this artist cut their hand with a razor blade in a work performed in front of an all-women audience. This artist\u2019s frequent collaborator (+) Francoise Masson photographed a work in which this artist clenched a rose in their teeth and ascended a metal ladder covered in sharp bits, titled Unanesthetized Escalation. This artist stated \u201cThere was no violence; my body hurt but I could feel my touch\u201d after finishing a work that was the fourth piece recreated by Marina Abramovi\u0107 in her series Seven Easy Pieces. For that work, this artist laid fully clothed on a metal (*) bed frame over two rows of lit candles. For 10 points, identify this French artist of Italian origin known for her performance The Conditioning.", "answer": "Gina Pane [The work in line three is Azione sentimentale.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Gina <b><u>Pane</u></b> [The work in line three is Azione sentimentale.]", "acceptable": ["Gina Pane", "Pane"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Description acceptable. Chicago\u2019s St. John Cantius Church contains a one-third scale copy of this artwork. After committing forgery, the artist of this work was branded with hot irons on his cheeks and sent away from the city where this work is housed to live in a city where he later created his sculpture Tobias and the Angel. In 2021, a five year restoration effort for this artwork found that it had been completed three years prior to its previously accepted completion date. This artwork was (+) stolen by the Nazis and kept in Nuremberg Castle until prisoners informed a resistance movement that it was hidden there. The top of this work depicts a coronation flanked by St. Stanislaus and St. Adalbert of Prague, and the center of this work depicts the (*) Dormition surrounded by the twelve Apostles in gold robes. For 10 points, identify this wooden Gothic pentaptych housed at St. Mary\u2019s Basilica in Krak\u00f3w, created by a German-born sculptor who worked there for over 20 years.", "answer": "Veit Stoss\u2019s altarpiece in Krak\u00f3w (accept Veit Sto\u00df, Veit Stuoss, or Wit Stwosz; accept St. Mary\u2019s Altar before \u201cSt. Mary;\u201d accept anything involving the Dormition or death of Mary in place of \u201caltarpiece\u201d)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Veit Stoss\u2019s altarpiece in Krak\u00f3w</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Veit Stoss\u2019s altarpiece in Krak\u00f3w", "Veit Stoss\u2019s altarpiece in Krak\u00f3w"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Veit Sto\u00df, Veit Stuoss, or Wit Stwosz; accept St. Mary\u2019s Altar before \u201cSt. Mary;\u201d accept anything involving the Dormition or death of Mary in place of \u201caltarpiece\u201d"}, {"question": "One of these objects appears on a piece of hand-painted blue ceramic in the work Odyssey Tile. A depiction of a nun leaving a milk factory appears in Xu Bing\u2019s work Dragonfly Eyes, which was created entirely using these objects. It\u2019s not a paint pot, but a 2006 sculpture replaces the head of an angel on a pedestal with one of these objects. Several of these objects are (+) mounted on the ceiling for the 2017 installation Hansel and Gretel, which was made five years after an artwork utilizing four of these objects by the same artist was shut down in less than two days. One of these objects appears to the right of a work showing a boy on a ladder (*) painting its title phrase on a wall as a dog and policeman look on. One of these objects was sculpted with marble by Ai Weiwei after several were installed in his studio by the Chinese government. For 10 points, identify these objects whose use is criticized in Banksy\u2019s One Nation, Under CCTV.", "answer": "security cameras (accept CCTV cameras or surveillance cameras)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>security cameras</u></b>", "acceptable": ["security cameras", "security cameras"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept CCTV cameras or surveillance cameras"}, {"question": "An artist from this country depicted the Twitter logo in black and white on a background of red and grey blocks in a work subtitled Whirlwind. A market gate from Miletus and the facade of the New York Stock Exchange appear in a painting by an artist from this country located in the entrance lobby of the Goldman Sachs tower. Five lines of red, white, and blue triangles reminiscent of (+) flags appear in the upper right of a work by an artist from this country. Thick trails of black stitching appear over a background of pastel geometric shapes in an entry from the Ants and Ceramicists series by an artist from this country. Curvy blocks of color and swirling lines appear over architectural drawings of the Hagia Sophia in an artwork from this non-Turkey country titled (*) Empirical Construction, Istanbul. An artist from this country often utilizes circuit components in his Tightrope series. For 10 points, name this African nation home to Elias Sime and Julie Mehretu.", "answer": "Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia [The work in line three is Mural by Julie Mehretu.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Federal Democratic Republic of <b><u>Ethiopia</u></b> [The work in line three is Mural by Julie Mehretu.]", "acceptable": ["Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia", "Ethiopia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in one of this artist\u2019s music videos swaps around the letters in the word \u201cINTRO\u201d to spell the word \u201cNITRO,\u201d after which it promptly explodes. One of this artist\u2019s music videos ends with its protagonist having a rainbow disc shoved in his back before becoming a many-armed bodhisattva. The music video to this artist\u2019s song (+) Let\u2019s Drop Dead features two exercising characters who had previously appeared with emojis for faces and drunkenly partying as ghosts in an earlier music video. This artist\u2019s signature \u201ccrying eye\u201d symbol appears on the hat of the character Bizu, the protagonist of the music video for his song SNOBBISM. The music video for this artist\u2019s most popular song opens with a shot of a boy with a piece of paper taped to his face sitting in an empty (*) classroom before several shots of red desks and chairs falling around him against a white background. For 10 points, identify this Vocaloid producer of Law-Evading Rock and Lost One\u2019s Weeping.", "answer": "Neru (accept z\u20195 or Oshiire-P) [The unnamed song in line four is Whatever, Whatever, Whatever.]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Neru</u></b> [The unnamed song in line four is Whatever, Whatever, Whatever.]", "acceptable": ["Neru", "Neru"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept z\u20195 or Oshiire-P"}], "bonuses": []}